<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><atom:link href="https://tankthinks.net" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><title>tankthinks</title><link>https://tankthinks.net</link><description>Like a think tank, but just me</description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 11:37:23 -0500</lastBuildDate><generator>clj-rss</generator><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-12-23-arachne/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-12-23-arachne/</link><title>Arachne</title><description>Sketchnote</description><pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-12-21-research-group-introduction/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-12-21-research-group-introduction/</link><title>Research Group Introduction and Application</title><description>Introduction</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-12-07-introduction-to-clojure/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-12-07-introduction-to-clojure/</link><title>Introduction to Clojure</title><description>++++</description><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-12-06-clojure-conj-sketchnotes/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-12-06-clojure-conj-sketchnotes/</link><title>Clojure Conj Sketchnotes</title><description>I recently attended Clojure/Conj, sketchnoting all of the talks I saw. I tweeted them after each session, however I wanted to collect them here too.Asher Corey's 40K LOCs to Build 1st Web Sonogram</description><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-02-15-superbetter/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-02-15-superbetter/</link><title>SuperBetter</title><description>The heart, soul, and extra-life of SuperBetter by Jane McGonigal is:</description><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-02-07-the-windup-bird-chronicles/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-02-07-the-windup-bird-chronicles/</link><title>The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle</title><description>The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle is a twisting dream from Haruki Murakami. A series of odd phone calls and the disappearance of a cat signal change, though Toru Okada doesn't realize it yet. When his wife Kumiko doesn't come home one day, Toru is forced to search for the source. His journey takes him into a literal deep well of dreams to find and return his life to normal.</description><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-01-31-when-getting-ahead-fails/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-01-31-when-getting-ahead-fails/</link><title>When Getting Ahead Failed Me</title><description>My last post was 3 weeks ago. What happened? Why am I so behind? Because I ran ahead, stumbled, and fell out of my habit.I have been reading at least a book a week for the past two months. 3 weeks ago I finished "Surely You're Joking Mr. Feynman" mid-week, grabbed "A Thousand Splendid Suns" which I finished by Friday night. I was stoked! I had finished 2 books before the weekend. I write these posts before bed on Sunday night so I had plenty of time to do my #sketchnote and post. Only I wasn't.</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-01-10-surely-youre-joking/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-01-10-surely-youre-joking/</link><title>Surely You're Joking Mr. Feynman</title><description>In his episodic memoir Surely You're Joking, Mr. Feynman, Richard Feynman wisks you away on his adventures through life, physics, music, art, love and - of course - safe-cracking.</description><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-01-03-norwegian-wood/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2016-01-03-norwegian-wood/</link><title>Norwegian Wood</title><description>Last week I read Norwegian Wood by Haruki Murakami. Many friends and colleagues have recommended Murakami over the years; however, this is the first of his I've read. Though I had heard any good things about The Wind-Up Bird Chronicle and Kafka on the Shore I decided to go with the more convential but less Murakami "Norwegian Wood" not for any literary reason but simply because that is what was available at the library and I love eponymous song by The Beatles.The theme of "Norwegian Wood" is responsibility: how responsibility changes as we mature and our responsibility for the happiness of ourselves and others. Murakami pays little attention the era of the 1960s, it seems as though the only reason for the novel's timeplace is its relation to the author's own experience. But no matter, for at its heart "Norwegian Wood" is a timeless coming of age love story.</description><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-12-27-of-dice-and-men/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-12-27-of-dice-and-men/</link><title>Of Dice and Men</title><description>I've always been nerdy (cereberal) and geeked (into) out on relatively obscure pop culture when I'm feeling dorky. (Forthcoming post to describe the canonical meanings of nerd, geek, and dork). In other words, I should have played Dungeons and Dragons when I was younger. But the wind finds the inner Grognard eventually. So when a new work friend told me he was creating a world and assuming the Dungeon Master mantle for the first time I downloaded the 300+ page PDF of D&amp;D rules 3.5 and rolled a Human Knight from a special order in my friends world. We start in January and I'm stoked.In honor of my first adventure I grabbed Of Dice and Men from my local library. It is an interesting book, half narrative and half exposition, it tells the tale of the author David M. Ewalt's refound love of D&amp;D while recounding it's history.</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-12-21-on-the-shortness-of-life/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-12-21-on-the-shortness-of-life/</link><title>On the Shortness of Life</title><description>The first thing you notice when you read Seneca is we have changed little in 2000 years. Yes we've progressed from wax tablets to iPhones but apparently we've come no closer to solving our mind's traps than Stoic philosophers.On the Shortness of Life by Seneca comprises three essays/letters written between 42 and 63 AD. "Consolation to Helvia" is a letter Seneca wrote to his mother shortly after his exile. Seneca alternates praising Helvia's courage with extolling the pleasantry of simple life. Exile is not bad, it is a gift.</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-12-14-shantaram/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-12-14-shantaram/</link><title>Shantaram</title><description>Last week I curled up with Shantaram by Gregory David Roberts, a book Tim Ferriss mentioned many times on his podcast. I didn't know anything about the book when I found it in the fiction stacks of my local library. Shantaram is a story of prison breaks, thievery, acceptance, kindness, warmth, loss, lost, love, treachery, and war. It is a book about being free.Loosly based on events in the author's life, Roberts' vivid descriptions of India, her life and culture, are the hearth of the book. The warmth emanates from Bombay's smiles, Sunder village's sustenance, the community of the zhopadpatti hutments, and Leopold's - Bombay's cousin to Rick's Cafe Americain.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-12-06-cuwab-1/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-12-06-cuwab-1/</link><title>Cuwab</title><description>My second grade teacher Ms. Cappabianca arranged comfy pillows in an otherwise odd nook in her classroom and put the word cuwab on the wall in funky construction paper letters. I remember it vividly even though it was over 26 years ago. I remember excitedly rushing to claim the best pillow before scanning the shelves to see if the Guinness Book of Records was still available.Did you duckduckgo cuwab yet? It does not exist on the internet! Amazing. It is an acronym for Curl Up With A B ook, and I intend to do so once a week starting now.</description><pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-11-30-3tilt-kickoff/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-11-30-3tilt-kickoff/</link><title>3tilt Kickoff</title><description>The learning principle is to plunge into the detailed mystery of the micro in order to understand what makes the macro tick.I've been recording "3 Things I Learned Today" off and on for the past year. I was inspired by Raju Gandhi's (@looselytyped) NFJS talk "Learning to Learn" a few years ago. In May I gave a career day presentation to 7th graders at my wife's school and told them to start a "3tilt" (3 things I learned today) journal. The things you learn don't have to be traditionally academic: you could learn how to beat a difficult mission in Starcraft II or even the train schedule. The point of the exercise is reflection, gratitude, and continuous learning.docker-compose is a good tool for dev testing
... especially if you're travelling down the microservices route where your app has several external resources. A few recommendations when using docker-compose:image &gt; build in the docker-compose configuration file: i.e. build the images for the app and its resources outside docker-compose and reference those prebuilt images from its configuration. Play around a bit, you'll see I'm right.upgrade to docker-compose v 1.5.0 or greater so you can use variable substitution in your image referencesremember that your links and environment are injected at docker "run" time, you can use the same images for testing and production with different environmentscreate links between Elastic Beanstalk environments
... much like docker-compose allows you to create links between containers, Elastic Beanstalk let's you create links between environments: simply create an env.yaml file in the root directory of your application (more precisely the root dir where you will call the eb cli) and follow AWS's always sensible randomized configuration file format.stories are powerful
... I grabbed Remapping Your Mind off the "New Non-Fiction" shelf of my local library when I returned Felicia Day's excellent memoir You're Never Weird on the Internet (almost). I love the brain and usually read any book with the words "synapse", "mind", "neuroscience", etc. on the cover. This book makes a compelling case for the position stories in medicine. The authors use a plethora of techniques ranging from NLP to Native American spirit quests to help patients recover from acute medical conditions. A real testament to the power of the mind and the true physiology of the brain.--  Josh Waitzkin The Art of Learning</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-11-29-dynamic-static-languages/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2015-11-29-dynamic-static-languages/</link><title>Dynamic vs Static Languages</title><description>Elben Shira's thoughtprovoking The End of Dynamic Languages inspired many wonderful responses, for example Have Static Languages Won?, What Consitutes Winning, and The Sky Is Not Falling.If Elben is offering odds then I will absolutely put money a new successful dynamic programming language for 3 reasons:</description><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-12-30-lamda-architecture/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-12-30-lamda-architecture/</link><title>5 Lamda Architecture Resources</title><description>Lambda Archiecture is fascinating Architectural Pattern. I first read about it while researching Apache Storm. Nathan Marz, the creator of Storm, discusses Lamda Archicture in his book Big Data: Principles and best practices of scalable realtime data systems. Here are some good resources for learning more.Runaway Complexity in Big Data and a Plan to Stop It Nathan Marz great slide deck on reducing complexity in Big Data.Nathan Marz on Storm, Immutability in the Lambda Architecture, Clojure Nathan Marz Q&amp;A from QCon 2014.Lambda Architecture: Design Simpler, Resilient, Maintainable and Scalable Big Data Solutions A great primer complete with working source code examples.Implementing the Lambda Architecture with Spring XD A nice presentation from SpringOne 2014 with multiple example implementations.Questions About the Lambda Architecture An interesting article summarizing some of the concerns about Lamda Architecture.</description><pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-05-27-java-service-rpm-example/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-05-27-java-service-rpm-example/</link><title>Java Service RPM Example</title><description>I just pushed a new repo Java Service RPM Example containing an example project for how to package your Java Microservice as an RPM for installation as a Linux SysV Init Script. I'll fill in this post in the days to come to let you know how it works.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-05-05-one-reason-clojure-is-great/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-05-05-one-reason-clojure-is-great/</link><title>Why Clojure is Great: Data</title><description>It is better to have 100 functions operate on one data structure than 10 functions on 10 data structures.--  Alan PerlisYou've probably seen this quote before. I've seen in in countless blogs and books. It is referenced in the wonderful Clojure book The Joy of Clojure. I recently experienced the joy of Clojure directly through Perlis' pearl of wisdom (all puns intended).</description><pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-04-04-refocus-simplify-1/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-04-04-refocus-simplify-1/</link><title>Simplify and Focus Learning</title><description>To learn, read. To know, write. To master, teach.--  anonymous Yogi Tea BagI've seen a version of this quote attributed to Yogi Bhajan; however, I first came across it on a Yogi Tea Bag.</description><pubDate>Fri, 04 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-04-02-four-ways-your-already-functional/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-04-02-four-ways-your-already-functional/</link><title>4 Ways Your Enterprise is Already Doing Functional Programming</title><description>Can't see the forest for the trees.--  idiom humansMost enterprise architectures are scared of functional programming. The funny thing is that they're probably already doing "functional" programming in Java, just poorly.</description><pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-30-microservices-1/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-30-microservices-1/</link><title>Microservices 1</title><description>Systems must be clean too. An invasive architecture overwhelms the domain logic and impacts agility.--  Bob Martin Clean CodeACT 1</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-17-run-length-decoding/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-17-run-length-decoding/</link><title>Run Length Decoding</title><description>...an idea is no more an even relatively constant thing than is a feeling or emotion or volitional process. There exist only changing and transient ideational processes; there are no permanent ideas that return again and disappear again.--  Wilhelm Wundt An Introduction to PsychologyComplexity and Likeablity</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-12-just-enough-design/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-12-just-enough-design/</link><title>Just Enough Design</title><description>Ticking away the moments that make up a dull day ...--  Pink Floyd TimeTick tick tick ...</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-10-where-is-the-oop-in-my-layers/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-10-where-is-the-oop-in-my-layers/</link><title>Where is the OOP in my Layers?</title><description>Help! I think I've lost the OOP in my Layers.Do I Smell Something?</description><pubDate>Mon, 10 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-08-property-based-testing/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-08-property-based-testing/</link><title>Property Based Testing</title><description>Found, but not proven.-- DemocritusPart of my learning Clojure journey is to question my beliefs regarding testing. For the past few years I've lived the Clean Code TDD style of development: let the rails of unit tests guide you. However, the Clojure brain trust - Rich, Stu and the rest of the brilliant minds at Cognitect have made a compelling argument that unit tests, or at least expectation-based tests are old hat.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-07-try_again/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-07-try_again/</link><title>Happiness and Coding</title><description>In the BeginningAm I the only one who feels like this?</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-01-ten-observations-from-scrumbut/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-01-ten-observations-from-scrumbut/</link><title>10 Observations From Scrumbut</title><description>ScrumbutWhat is scrumbut?</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item><item><guid>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-01-i-wonder/</guid><link>https://tankthinks.net/posts-output/2014-03-01-i-wonder/</link><title>I wonder</title><description>I think my brother is coming into an opportunity. He is working at a new company that has lots of room for improvement. I asked him to bring a notebook to work and note any inefficiencies he comes across.It got me thinking that I could free-lance for this company. However, I wonder if I have the skills to architect large solutions. I think I'm a strong software developer. I must not be an idiot because Yaning thinks I'm pretty smart. I think Peter thouht I was smart too. However, I did not do well in the HubSpot interview. Though that is really confusing to me.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate></item></channel></rss>